#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/dominic-james-111136145 (LinkedIn)

#### Top Skills

OpenShift
Transport Layer Security (TLS)
Proxy Server

Certifications
SOFT SKILL AQUISITION
Jira Fundament Batch
EF STANDARD ENGLISH TEST
CERTIFICATE
Scrum Fundamentals Certified (SFC)

# **Dominic James**

Software Engineer || .NET CORE || C# || BackEnd Engineer || MSSQL || Entity Framework || Scrum

Lagos, Lagos State, Nigeria

### Summary

About me

As a seasoned software engineer with over three years of experience, I have specialized in implementing efficient backend systems utilizing .Net Core. My strong leadership skills have enabled me to successfully lead the re-architecture and development of two applications, both of which are currently in production. I have demonstrated proficiency in rapidly learning new technologies and leveraging them to deliver effective solutions to intricate problems

#### **Key Achievements**

 For my final year project in the university i Developed a web Based System for the issuance of an Indigen Certificate for Ogbadibo Local Government Area of Benue State

Throughout my academic & professional career, I remained passionate about assessing emerging technologies to develop thoughtful and innovative ideas.

Core Skills & Expertise

C#, HTML || CSS || JavaScript || React || .Net || SQL || Git || Scrum || AGILE Methodologies || Superior Communication || Team Management || Time Management & Computer System Proficiency

**SKILLS** 

C#, .Net, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Micro Services, AZURE

### Experience

ExamRoom.Al® Backend Engineer

#### February 2023 - Present (1 year)

Nigeria

- Refactored the previous code base on Credentia GIS project from a monolithic application to a microservice.
- • Collaborated on stages of the systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.
- Utilized C# written against the latest .NET stack to develop micro-services hosted on Azure, employing Kubernetes for new implementations.
- Contributed to the ongoing iteration towards a completely decoupled, eventdriven architecture across the entire software portfolio.
- Refactored the Credentia GIS project from a monolithic application to a micro-service, enhancing scalability and performance.
- Revised, modularized, and updated old code bases to modern development standards, reducing operating costs, and improving functionality.
- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre- release software project development.
- Discussed issues with team members to provide solution and apply best practices.
- Translated customer requirements into written use cases.

#### Decagon

Software Engineer

January 2021 - February 2023 (2 years 2 months)

Benin City, Edo, Nigeria

C# || .Net || HTML, CSS & JavaScript || Agile || SCRUM Fundamental || React

- Influenced the development of a cutting-edge platform that facilitated the adoption of technology and financial inclusion for Users in Nigeria.
- Collaborated with a team of 5 elite engineers to design and implement 3 key features of the super admin section of the application, resulting in a 25% increase in user engagement.
- Consumed and rendered 20 APIs as required to improve the overall functionality of the platform.
- Consistently delivered tasks within tight deadlines, resulting in a 95% completion rate and a commitment to delivering high-quality code.
- Designed applications and website objectives by analyzing user requirements; and envisioning system features and functionality
- Collaborated on stages of the systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.

- Improved application usability and tweaked security features on vulnerable software
- Created robust, clean, and maintainable code Implemented decoupled and clean architecture for applications
- Developed, tested, maintained, and supported web applications for clients

## Education

Federal University of Technology Minna Bachelors, Computer Science · (2014 - 2021)